Guide to the Augustus Ward Loomis papers, 1803-1897
Loomis, Augustus Ward papers, 1803-1897
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Augustus Ward Loomis papers, 1803-1897.
2474
Augustus Ward. Loomis
.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, deeds, bonds, lists, sketches, photographs, bound volumes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes letters to relatives in Cazenovia, New York, from Augustus Ward Loomis and his wife, Mary Ann, Presbyterian missionaries to Chekiang Province, China (1845-1849), Indian Territory (1852), and to the Chinese in San Francisco (1865-1867). Also included are papers (1803-1849) of Ward's father, Seba Loomis, among them deeds for lands in Coventry, Connecticut, and Cazenovia, New York; a survey of his farm in Road Township, Madison County, New York; debtors' writs from Tolland County, Connecticut; a blacksmith's apprenticeship indenture from Windham County, Connecticut; and his will.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes letters to relatives in Cazenovia, New York, from Augustus Ward Loomis and his wife, Mary Ann, Presbyterian missionaries to Chekiang Province, China (1845-1849), Indian Territory (1852), and to the Chinese in San Francisco (1865-1867). These letters are mainly concerned with the Loomis' religious views and activities, their impressions of the places to which they traveled, in particular Hong Kong, Canton, Chusan, and Ningpo, China; Chicago and Galesburg, Illinois; St. Charles, Missouri; Little Rock, Arkansas; and Cowetah and Tullahassee, Oklahoma; and with their evaluation of the Chinese and the Creek and Cherokee Indians. They also mention such events and issues as the defeat of Winfield Scott in the presidential election of 1852 and the election of Gerrit Smith to Congress in the same year, the volume of the migration to California and Oregon (1852-1853), the railroad fever in St. Louis (1853), the question of slavery and whether it was right to buy slaves and allow them to work for their freedom, the assassination of Lincoln, and the capture of Jefferson Davis. Also included are papers (1803-1849) of Ward's father, Seba Loomis, among them deeds for lands in Coventry, Connecticut, and Cazenovia, New York; a survey of his farm in Road Township, Madison County, New York; debtors' writs from Tolland County, Connecticut; a blacksmith's apprenticeship indenture from Windham County, Connecticut; and his will.
Also, papers (1833-1897) of Ward's brother, Edwin Dwight Loomis, among them deeds, bonds, and other documents for land in Cazenovia and Georgetown, New York, and in Campbell County, Dakota Territory, and General Land Office patents and a deed, with related letters from a cousin, George H. Jerome of Iowa City, for War of 1812 bounty lands in Adams County, Iowa. Also includes deeds and other legal papers involving Jonathan D. Ledyard and members of the Ingersoll, Prentiss, Root, and Sweetland families of Cazenovia and Georgetown; naturalization papers of Robert and William Dawson of Pamelia, Jefferson County, New York (1866); and records (1862-1864) of the New England Company, a subsidiary of J. C. Tillotson & Company of Cazenovia, including minutes of the board of directors (among whom were E. D. Loomis and another brother, Silas Lathrop Loomis), lists of share subscribers in Berkshire County, Massachusetts, and bills and receipts; and obituaries and family memorabilia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Loomis, Augustus Ward.; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889.; Dawson, Robert.; Dawson, William.; Ingersoll family.; Jerome, George H.; Ledyard, Jonathan D.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865--Assassination.; Loomis family.; Loomis, Edwin Dwight.; Loomis, Mary Ann.; Loomis, Seba.; Loomis, Silas Lathrop.; Prentiss family.; Root family.; Scott, Winfield, 1837-1910.; Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874.; Sweetland family.; J. C. Tillotson & Company.; New England Company.
Subjects:
Cherokee Indians.; Creek Indians.; Missionaries--China.; Missionaries--California--San Francisco.; Presbyterians.; Presidents--United States--Election--1852.; Real property, Exchange of.; Religion.; Slavery.; Missionaries.; Women missionaries.
Places:
Zhejiang Sheng (China); China.
Form and Genre Terms:
Deeds.; Patents.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Poem by Bethuel Parker, Apr. 4, 1795 (Folder 1)
  Original and a copy made later (omitted from Report dating)
- Warranty Deed from Alice Loomis & [Eliphalet Hendy?], Coventry, Tolland Co., Conn., to Seba Loomis (father of AWL), Coventry, Tolland Co., Conn., Rec. Apr. 27, 1803 (Folder 1)
  Regards land in Coventry.
- Warranty Deed from Seba Loomis, Coventry, Tolland Co., Conn., to Alice Loomis, Coventry, Tolland Co., Conn., Rec. Dec. 5, 1803 (Folder 1)
- Indenture from Ebenezer Moseley, Hampton, Windham Co., Conn., to Seba Loomis., Jan. 2, 1804 (Folder 1)
  Three year blacksmithing apprenticeship of Moseley's son, Elethan, to Loomis.
- Debtor's Writ from State of Connecticut to Tolland County Sheriff or Town of Coventry Constables., Dec. 20, 1816 (Folder 1)
  Collecting debt for Sylvester Carver of Bolton in Tolland Co. Note from David Smith of Coventry for $4.08 & cost of fees.
- Debtor's Writ from State of Connecticut to Tolland County Sheriff or Town of Coventry Constables., Dec. 20, 1816 (Folder 1)
  Imprisonment of debtor David Smith of Coventry for non-payment of debt, signed by Ichabod M. Warner, Justice of the Peace at Bolton, Conn.
- Warranty Deed from Isaac Lyman & his wife Polly and Selah Munson & his wife Margery, Cazenovia, New York, to Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. May 14, 1818 (Folder 1)
  Regards Cazenovia, New York propery.
- Warranty Deed from Isaac Ingersoll & his wife Irene, Cazenovia, New York, to Seba Loomis, Cazenovia New York., June 15, 1827 (Folder 1)
  Regards Cazenovia, New York property.
- Warranty Deed from Ezra Jenkins, Cazenovia, New York, to Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Feb. 12, 1828 (Folder 1)
- Letter from Edwin D. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to Mr. Augustus Loomis, Albany, New York., June 25, 1833 (Folder 1)
  Family news.
- Warranty Deed from Roswell Cott & Margaret, his wife of Baltimore, Md., to Thomas Root, Mexico [Oswego Co., New York]., Rec. Sept. 23, 1835 (Folder 1)
  Regards Oswego Co. property.
- Indenture from I. Ingersoll, Samuel C. Ingersoll, William Ingersoll, E. Ingersoll, Henry A. Johnson & Lydia, his wife, Nelson Prentiss & E., his wife, and Albert Ingersoll to Talcott Backus, n.p., Rec. May 10, 1838 (Folder 1)
- Letter from [AWL] & Mary Ann Loomis on board ship Issabella [sic] Anna to Silas L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Feb. 20, 1845 - Mar. 29, 1845 (Folder 2)
  Describes Hong Kong & their travels.
- Bond from Eldad W. Ingersoll & Albert Ingersoll, Cazenovia, New York, to Talcott Backus, Cazenovia, New York., Apr. 1, 1845 (Folder 2)
  Regards borrowing money.
- Mortgage from Eldad W. Ingersoll & Albert Ingersoll, Cazenovia, New York, to Talcott Backus, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Apr. 21, 1845 (Folder 2)
- Letter from Mary Ann [Loomis], Ningpo, [Chekiang Province, China] to My dear sister Mary [Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis], Cazenovia, New York., Feb. 25, 1848 (Folder 2)
  Happenings in Ningpo.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Dear Sister Mary [Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis], Cazenovia, New York., July 17, 1848 (Folder 2)
  Mary Ann teaches little Chinese girls, pirates on the sea.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Sept. 9, 1848 (Folder 2)
  Mary Ann is sick with fever and ague and happenings around Ningpo.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to My dear Parents., Oct. 18, 1848 (Folder 2)
  Their travels around Ningpo.
- Letter from A. W. & Mary Ann Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Mr. Silas L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Nov. 17, 1848 (Folder 2)
  Their missionary work & typhoon in Shanghai in July or August.
- Letter from A. W. & Mary Ann Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Mr. Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Jan. 1, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Their missionary work.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Mar. 14, 1849 (Folder 2)
  A procession in the neighborhood honoring an idol god & missionary work.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to My dear Father [Mr. Seba Loomis], Cazenovia, New York., May 2, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Sending package home to Cazenovia.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Miss Fanny Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., May 7, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Inquires of happenings in Cazenovia, house cleaning in his house, talks of religion.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Mr. Edwin D. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., June 8, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Missionary work, AWL not to preach for a while.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Ningpo [China] to Dear Sister Mary, n.p., June 18, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Happenings around Ningpo, sickness.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Chusan [Chekiang Province, China] to My Dear Parents, n.p., July 4, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Weather conditions, navigation difficulties at mouth of river, and missionary work.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Chusan [China] to Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., July 27, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Inquires of family news.
- Letter from [A. W. Loomis], Chusan [China] to Dear Parents., August 2, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Weather and sickness.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, n.p. to [Dear Parents], n.p., August 15, [1849?] (Folder 2)
  Arrived Ningpo, sickness.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Coast of China on board ship Great Briton [sic] to Mr. Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Sept. 24, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Weather; their diseases increase daily, he has throat trouble, doctor wants Mary Ann to return to US soon.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Canton [China] to Mr. Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Oct. 10, 1849 (Folder 2)
  They have taken first boat for US, stopped at Canton; AWL has bronchitis.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Canton [capital of Kwangtung Province, China] to Dear Parents., Oct. 23, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Waiting for passage to US.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Canton [China] to Mr. Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Nov. 18, 1849 (Folder 2)
  Still waiting for passage from Canton to US, visited a Buddhist temple.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Canton [China] to Mr. Silas L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Dec 10, 1849 (Folder 2)
  "probably leave here about the middle of December and the captain counts on about 110 days passage."
- Will of Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, Madison Co., New York., Dec. 24, 1849 (Folder 2)
- Deed from Zudic? Zadock?, Lucy & Sarah Sweetland, Cazenovia, New York, to E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Apr. 10, 1850 (Folder 3)
- Letter from E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to Dear Son Thomas [Thomas R. Loomis], Mexico, Oswego County, New York., Dec. 18, 1850 (Folder 3)
- Deed from Joseph & John White, Trustees of the Cazenovia South Burying Ground, to E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Feb. 3, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Sale of burial lots.
- Deed from John A. & Mary King, Jamaica, Queens County, New York, to William Sherman, Georgetown, Madison County, New York., Mar. 17, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Regards Georgetown, New York property.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Galesburg [Illinois] to My Dear Sister Jane, n.p., Apr. 26, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Describing trip from New York to Galesburg, Illinois - "Arabia deserta" - observations of oxen and horse wagons of western emigrants.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Little Rock, Arkansas, to Mr. Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., May 18, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Describes the country around Little Rock & says they are going among the Creek Indians as missionaries; mentions meeting other missionaries who are going among the Cherokees.
- Letter from Mary Ann [in the West], n.p., to no name given, n.p., May 23, [1852] (Folder 3)
  Inquires of the family, mentions Creek Indians.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, Kowetah [Cowetah, Oklahoma] to My Dear Parents, n.p., Oct. 7, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Mary Ann has fever & ague, is at Tullahassee; "I am now a man I have seen the world at home & abroad for 35 years"; discusses the question of slavery. Mentions visit to Cherokee Country.
- Letter from AWL, Tullahassee, Oklahoma, to Dear Brother Lathrop, n.p., Dec. 21, 1852 (Folder 3)
  Discusses the recent presidential election & the election of Garit [sic] Smith to Congress and the Creek Indians - "not as bad as Cherokees."
- Deed from William J. Hough & Clarinda C., his wife, Cazenovia, New York, to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. February 23, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Bond from Silas L. Loomis & Edwin Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to William Sherman, Georgetown, Madison County, New York., Mar. 25, 1853. (Folder 3)
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, St. Charles on the Missouri River (20 miles N.E. of St. Louis) to My Dear Parents, n.p., Apr. 4, [1853?] (Folder 3)
  Major George C. Sibley starting "Linden Wood Female College."
- Letter from A. W. and Mary Ann Loomis, St. Charles, [Missouri] to Mrs. Mary Ann Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Apr. 21, 1853 (Folder 3)
  Tells of the coming of the railroads to St. Louis.
- Contract from Asa Ellis, Georgetown, New York, to E. D. Loomis & S. L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., June 13, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Contract from Thomas W. Ludlow, Yonkers, Westchester County, New York, to E. D. & S. L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., June 13, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Deed from John A. King & wife, Mary, Jamaica, Queens County, New York, to Silas L. Loomis and Edwin Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Oct. 20, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Deed from Job Mack & Mary his wife, Georgetown, New York, to E. Dwight and S. L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Oct. 20, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Deed from Thomas W. Ludlow & Frances W. his wife, Yonkers,Westchester County, New York, to S. L. & E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Apr. 9, 1855 (Folder 3)
- Letter from G. H. Jerome, Iowa City, Iowa [a cousin of Dwight Loomis, who was also related to Jennie Jerome Churchill, Winston's mother] to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Mar. 20, 1856 (Folder 3)
  Iowa land transactions.
- Letter from George H. Jerome, Iowa City, Iowa, to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Apr. 3, 1856 (Folder 3)
- Deed from Seba Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Feb. 24, 1857 (Folder 3)
- Deed from Jonathan D. Ledyard, Cazenovia, New York, to E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Feb. 24, 1857 (Folder 3)
- Letter from G. H. Jerome, Iowa City, Iowa, to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Mar. 16, 1857 (Folder 3)
  Iowa farm land.
- Agreement from S. L. & E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to Eldad Ingersoll, Cazenovia, New York., Mar. 23, 1857 (Folder 3)
  Renting Georgetown, New York property.
- Letter from G. H. Jerome, Iowa City, Iowa, to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Apr. 15, 1857 (Folder 3)
  Investing in Iowa land.
- Land Patent from James Buchanan, U.S. President, Washington, D.C., to George H. Jerome, assignee of Emile Bouchereau., Apr. 1, 1858 (Folder 3)
  Granting land in Adams County, Iowa for military service of Bouchereau; sale took place in Chariton, Lucas County.
- Letter from Henry Loomis, Iowa City, Iowa, to Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Jan. 24, 1859 (Folder 4)
  Paying taxes on Iowa land.
- Land Patent from U. S. Govt signed by President James Buchanan, Washington, D.C., to George H. Jerome, Assignee of Giles Blagne., July 1, 1859 (Folder 4)
  Granting 120 acres of bounty land in Adams County, Iowa for service in War of 1812.
- Certificated from George F. Sherman, Inspector General, and Frederick Townsend, Adjutant General, N.Y.S. M[ilitia], to Thomas Root, Cazenovia, New York., July 4, 1859 (Folder 4)
  $32.00 due Root after they audited & revised Root's claim.
- Agreement from Silas L. and E. D. Loomis of Town of Cazenovia to Joseph Curtis, Town of DeRuyter, Madison Co. New York., July 1, 1862 (Folder 4)
  Sale of Georgetown property.
- Minutes, J. C. Tillotson and Company, Cazenovia, New York., July 1, 1862 (Folder 4)
  Meeting - O. W. Loomis appointed a director, S. L. Loomis on committee.
- Constitution, C. June 30, 1862 (Folder 4)
  Adopted by the subscribed members of J. C. Tillotson & Co. and known as the New England Co. for the sale of Larrow[e] patent self adusting brake.
- Minutes of the [J. C. Tillotson or New England?] Co. meeting., Aug. 8, [1862?] (Folder 4)
  Voted to raise $500 to defray expenses and pay all necessary output for the transaction of business.
- Bill from A. T. Cross(?) and Son to J. C. Tillotson & Co., n.p., Aug. 19, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Buying merchandise.
- Receipt from Francis A. Crandall, Cazenovia, New York, to J. C. Tillotson, W. B. Child, n.p., Aug. 26, 1863 (Folder 4)
  For printing 100 blank patent right deeds.
- List of Subscribers, Aug. 26, 1863 (Folder 4)
  List of subscribers who agree to pay for shares for the purpose of securing the exclusive right to make, use, or sell A. Larrow's self acting wagon brake in and to the Town of Lenox, Berkshire Co., Mass. Agreement made with J. C. Tillotson & Co.
- List of Subscribers, Aug. 29, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except in the Town of Lee, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- List of Subscribers, Sept. 7, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Pittsfield, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- List of Subscribers, Sept. 17, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Lanesborough, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- Certificate, Sept. 23, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Certificate that a deed was received from J. C. Tillotson & Co., for the exclusive right to make, use, or sell A. Larrow's self acting wagon brake in and to the Town of Lanesborough, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- List of Subscribers, Sept. 29, 1863 (Folder 4)
  List of subscribers who agree to pay for shares for the purpose of securing the exclusive right to make, use or sell A. Larrow's self acting wagon brake in and to the Town of Stockbridge, Berkshire Co., Mass. Agreement made with J. C. Tillotson & Co.
- List of Subscribers, Oct. 16, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Alford, Berkshire Co.
- List of Subscribers, Oct. 17, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Egremont, Berkshire Co.
- List of Subscribers, Nov. 12, 1863 (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Cheshire, Berkshire Co.
- List of Subscribers, Oct. 6, no year. [1863?] (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of West Stockbridge, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- List of Subscribers, n.d. [1863?] (Folder 4)
  List of subscribers who agree to pay for shares for the purpose of securing the exclusive right to make, use or sell A. Larrow's self acting wagon brake in and to the Town of Monterey, Berkshire Co., Mass. Agreement made with J. C. Tillotson & Co.
- List of Subscribers, n.d. [1863?] (Folder 4)
  Same as above except for the Town of Great Barrington, Berkshire Co., Mass.
- List of receipts from East Town regarding brake business., 1863? (Folder 4)
- Statement of amount paid S. Hill, an employee of the Brake Co. and expenses., 1863? (Folder 5)
- Deed from E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to Silas L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Feb. 24, 1864 (Folder 5)
- Receipted Bill to J. C. Tillotson & Co., Aug. 12, 1864 (Folder 5)
  For work done by A. T. Cross & Son for $6.00.
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, San Francisco [California] to Dear Sister Jane, n.p., May 15, 1865 (Folder 5)
  Teaching the Chinese & family news.
- Certificate from A. J. Shelley, Deputy Clerk, Jefferson County, Watertown, New York, to Robert Dawson, Pamelia, Jefferson County, New York., Oct. 19, 1866 (Folder 5)
  Citizenship paper.
- Certificate from A. J. Shelley, Deputy Clerk, Jefferson County, Watertown, New York, to Robert Dawson, Pamelia, Jefferson County, New York., Oct. 19, 1866 (Folder 5)
- Deed from E. Dwight & Mary Jane Loomis, n.p. to Silas L. Loomis, n.p., Mar. 6, 1867 (Folder 5)
- Letter with family news from A. Ward Loomis, San Francisco [California] to Ward (My Dear Nephew), n.p., June 29, 1867 (Folder 5)
- Letter from A. W. Loomis, San Francisco, California, to Dear Friends at Stockbridge (envelope addressed to Mr. Henry Gaston, Munnsville, Madison County, N.Y.), Sept. 17, 1867 (Folder 5)
  A. W. L.'s activities (teaching a Chinese man.)
- Deed from George H. Jerome & wife, Charlotte D., Johnson County, Iowa, to E. Dwight Loomis, Madison County, New York., Rec. Mar. 3, 1868 (Folder 5)
  Quit claim deed for land in Adams County, Iowa.
- Notice announcing an act passed by Congress for the granting of pensions for service in the War of 1812 from the National War Claim Agency, Cleveland, Ohio., Feb. 1871 (Folder 5)
- Blank form for a Declaration for Pension, War of 1812, Feb. 14, 1871 (Folder 5)
- Certificate from Bank of Cazenovia, Cazenovia, New York, to E. Dwight Loomis. Loomis had 7 shares of capital stock., Jan. 15, 1875 (Folder 5)
- Receipt from Bank of Cazenovia, J. C. Tillotson, Receiver, to E. Dwight Loomis., Mar. 22, 1876 (Folder 5)
  Receipt of $166.75 & $2.56.
- Deed from Silas L. Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Aug. 29, 1877 (Folder 5)
- Bond from E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York, to Theodore F. Huntley, Cazenovia, New York., Nov. 23, 1882 (Folder 5)
  Borrowing money.
- Mortgage Note from W. W. McDonald, Trustee, Western Loan & Trust Company, Pierre, Dakota Territory, to Andrew D. Singar?[er?], Campbell County, Dakota Territory., Oct. 5, 1887 (Folder 5)
  First mortgage & real estate note.
- Copy of Will of E. Dwight Loomis, Cazenovia, New York., Rec. Mar. 19, 1897 (Folder 6)
- Inventory of household goods, chattels & credits of the E. Dwight Loomis estate by Andrew M. Smith & Thomas H. White., Mar. 27, 1897 (Folder 6)
- Bill from Barney Riley, Cazenovia, New York, to Mr. Dwite [sic] Loomis, n.p. [estate of]., Nov. 6, 1897 (Folder 6)
  Bill for horseshoeing.
- Stock Certificate from Jasper Stone Company, Sioux City, Iowa, to E. D. Loomis Estate, n.p., July 7, 1908 (Folder 6)
  Regards preferred stock.
- Typescript of Legal Form - Application for Letters of Administration of the Estate of E. Dwight Loomis., 1912 or later (Folder 6)
- Letter from Bess [New York City, New York] to Dearest Aunt [Miss G. S. Loomis], Rome, New York., Aug. 2, 1933 (Folder 6)
- Letter from Silas Lathrop Loomis, Womelsdorf, Berks County, Pa., to Honoured Parents (Mr. Seba Loomis), Cazenovia, New York., June 22 (no year) (Folder 7)
  His being in Pa. & his views of life.
- Letter from Jane Thomas, n.p., to My Dear Grand-Parents (Mr. & Mrs. Root), n.p. [Mexico, New York?] (Folder 7)
  Family news & samples of hair.
- Letter from Julia S. Loomis, n.p., to Dear Mother, n.p., Wed. afternoon (Folder 7)
- Letter from Mary Ann and A. W. Loomis, San Rafael [California] to My dear Sister Jane, n.p., May 24th [presumably 1865] (Folder 7)
  Mentions murder of Lincoln and capture of Jeff Davis, inquires about family, "General Lee as a gentleman murderer of thousands of his prisoners."
- Manuscript Sheets, 1847 (Folder 7)
  Undated note on a Warranty Deed, which was dated Mar. 24, 1847 and Rec. Apr. 6, 1847, and sketch of same land.
  Sketch of a plot of land showing a mill, dam, and a flume.
- Poem, "The Dearer Dead", n.d. (Folder 7)
- Survey by S. L. Loomis, Surveyor of Seba Loomis farm in Road Township (Madison County) reservation, n.d. (Folder 7)
- Watercolor of two roses (portions of map on reverse) (Folder 8)
- Pictures of Ward Loomis (AWL's nephew?) (Folder 8)
  1. About 3 years
  2. About 9 years
- "Julia's curl" (1 loose piece of brown hair) (Folder 8)
- 1 Book Mark - "Cousin Jerusha" (Folder 8)
- Obituary of Edwin Dwight Loomis, n.d., no newspaper, and obituary of Mrs. Edwin Dwight Loomis (Mary Jane Root), n.d., no newspaper. (Folder 8)
- "Our Father's Care." (pamphlet) Philadelphia: American Sunday-School Union. 34 pp. (Ward) (Folder 8)
- School Book (torn fragment in poor condition) (Folder 8)
- Typescript copies of letters (set #1) (Folder 10)
- Typescript copies of letters (set #2) (Folder 11)